International Workers Order (IWO) Records 5276
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- National Women's Committee, 1941 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  Minutes of meeting, 3/19/41, 2 pages.
- Negroes, 1941-1949 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  3 page letter to the editor of The Daily Compass from Edward L. Nelson, New Haven, Connecticut, in disagreement with an editorial by a Mr. Ottley concerning the Negro people's progress in general (includes several drafts) (ff 9); 3 page "Minutes of the Na
- Negroes, 1941-1949 (Box 19, Folder 10)
- Negroes, 1941-1949 (Box 19, Folder 11)
- Negroes, 1941-1949 (Box 19, Folder 12)
- Negroes, 1941-1949 (Box 19, Folder 12a)
- People's Radio Association (Box 61, Folder 3)
  Form letter sent out to potential sponsors for PRA.
- Peoples Songs, Inc., 1946 (Box 61, Folder 4)
  Brochures and newsletter re songs of labor.
- Politics, 1942-1944 (Box 61, Folder 5)
  Articles; endorsements of IWO by state; broadsides; news clippings; "Report on Movie Tours and Showings During Election Campaign," 4 pages, 1944.
- Politics, 1942-1944 (Box 61, Folder 6)
- Politics, 1942-1944 (Box 61, Folder 7)
- Publications - Requests for, 1944-1946 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  Routine requests for IWO publications.
- Publications - Requests for, 1944-1946 (Box 20, Folder 2)
- Publications - Requests for, 1944-1946 (Box 20, Folder 3)
- Publications Department - Negro History Week, 1947 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  Order blanks; plan of publicity and promotion; news releases and routine re publications to be issued.
- Publication Department - Requests for Film Strip, 1946 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  Requests for film strip "Health and Security for America," by IWO.
- Publications Department - Requests - "Negro History Week Bulletin", 1947 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  Includes routine requests for publications.
- Publications Department - Requests - "Negro History Week Bulletin", 1947 (Box 20, Folder 7)
- Publications Department - Requests - "Negro History Week Bulletin", 1947 (Box 20, Folder 8)
- Radio Programs (Box 20, Folder 9)
  Form re IWO broadcasts.
- Radio Project (Box 20, Folder 10)
  Re suggestions for project re Russian Radio Project (some handwritten pages).
- Relief and Rehabilitation, 1946 (Box 20, Folder 10a)
  Correspondence, news releases, requests for publication, re United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration's distribution of food to invaded countries.
- Roosevelt, F. D., 1941-1943 (Box 61, Folder 8)
  Includes newspaper clippings, 8 page "President Roosevelt's Radio Address - George Washington's Birthday, 2/22/48."
- Salvage and Conservation, 1942 (Box 61, Folder 9)
  Broadside and government publication.
- Servicemen's Vote, 1944 (Box 61, Folder 10)
  Publications.
- Servicemen's Welfare, 1944 (Box 61, Folder 11)
  "Memorandum on Servicemen's Welfare, Prepared for Brother Bedacht, September 1941-April 1944," 4 pages, re gifts sent to servicemen by IWO.
- Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 1517, 1953-2002 (Box 61, Folder 12)
  Correspondence re payment of sick benefit claims to members of Slovak local lodges. (Unable to translate some of this correspondence.)
- Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 1517, 1953-2002 (Box 61, Folder 13)
- Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 1517, 1953-2002 (Box 61, Folder 14)
- Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 1517, 1953-2002 (Box 61, Folder 15)
- Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 1517, 1953-2002 (Box 61, Folder 16)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 2005-3548, 1950-1953 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  Correspondence re payment of sick benefit claims to members of Slovak local lodges, appears to be all Slovak locals. (Unable to translate most of box.)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 2005-3548, 1950-1953 (Box 21, Folder 2)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 2005-3548, 1950-1953 (Box 21, Folder 3)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 2005-3548, 1950-1953 (Box 21, Folder 4)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 2005-3548, 1950-1953 (Box 21, Folder 5)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 2005-3548, 1950-1953 (Box 21, Folder 6)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 2005-3548, 1950-1953 (Box 21, Folder 7)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 2005-3548, 1950-1953 (Box 21, Folder 8)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 2005-3548, 1950-1953 (Box 21, Folder 9)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 2005-3548, 1950-1953 (Box 21, Folder 10)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 2005-3548, 1950-1953 (Box 21, Folder 11)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 2005-3548, 1950-1953 (Box 21, Folder 12)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 2005-3548, 1950-1953 (Box 21, Folder 13)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 2005-3548, 1950-1953 (Box 21, Folder 14)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 2005-3548, 1950-1953 (Box 21, Folder 15)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 2005-3548, 1950-1953 (Box 21, Folder 16)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 2005-3548, 1950-1953 (Box 21, Folder 17)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 2005-3548, 1950-1953 (Box 21, Folder 18)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 2005-3548, 1950-1953 (Box 21, Folder 19)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 2005-3548, 1950-1953 (Box 21, Folder 20)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 2005-3548, 1950-1953 (Box 21, Folder 21)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 2005-3548, 1950-1953 (Box 21, Folder 22)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 2005-3548, 1950-1953 (Box 21, Folder 23)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 2005-3548, 1950-1953 (Box 21, Folder 24)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 2005-3548, 1950-1953 (Box 21, Folder 25)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 2005-3548, 1950-1953 (Box 21, Folder 26)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 2005-3548, 1950-1953 (Box 21, Folder 27)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 2005-3548, 1950-1953 (Box 21, Folder 28)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 2005-3548, 1950-1953 (Box 21, Folder 29)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 2005-3548, 1950-1953 (Box 21, Folder 30)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 2005-3548, 1950-1953 (Box 21, Folder 31)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 2005-3548, 1950-1953 (Box 21, Folder 32)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 2005-3548, 1950-1953 (Box 21, Folder 33)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 2005-3548, 1950-1953 (Box 21, Folder 34)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 2005-3548, 1950-1953 (Box 21, Folder 35)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 2005-3548, 1950-1953 (Box 21, Folder 36)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 2005-3548, 1950-1953 (Box 61, Folder 17)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 2005-3548, 1950-1953 (Box 61, Folder 18)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 2005-3548, 1950-1953 (Box 61, Folder 19)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 2005-3548, 1950-1953 (Box 62, Folder 1)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 3549-3579 (Box 22, Folder 1)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 4012 (Box 22, Folder 2)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 4251-4254 (Box 22, Folder 3)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 4255-4257 (Box 22, Folder 4)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 4258-4266 (Box 22, Folder 5)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 4268-4272 (Box 22, Folder 6)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 4273-4276 (Box 22, Folder 7)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 4278-4283 (Box 22, Folder 8)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 4286-4290 (Box 22, Folder 9)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 4292-4296 (Box 22, Folder 10)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 4297-4299 (Box 22, Folder 11)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 4300-4305 (Box 22, Folder 12)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 4307-4314 (Box 22, Folder 13)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 4316-4333 (Box 22, Folder 14)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 4339-4351 (Box 22, Folder 15)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 4355-4363 (Box 62, Folder 2)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 4366-4372 (Box 62, Folder 3)
- SBD (Sick Benefit Department - Lodge 4373-4385 (Box 62, Folder 4)
- Social Security Crusade Fund, 1940-1941 (Box 62, Folder 5)
  Statistical/financial sheets, "Report of Income."
- Soviet-Nazi War, 1941 (Box 62, Folder 6)
  6 page "Speakers' Guide on the Soviet-Nazi War and Its Significance to Americans."
- United Nations, 1942 (Box 62, Folder 7)
  Includes publications, Declaration by the U.N., copy of the Atlantic Charter, and brochures.
- United Office and Professional Workers, Local 16, 1949 (Box 62, Folder 8)
  Union represented National Office staff of IWO - Includes correspondence, seniority lists, agreement and supplemental agreement
- Veterans Work, 1945 (Box 62, Folder 9)
  Correspondence form Dave Green re benefits for veterans; news releases; broadsides; form letters.
- War Relief, 1942 (Box 62, Folder 10)
  Release; pamphlet; article re war relief.
- Win the Peace Conference, 1946 (Box 62, Folder 11)
  Releases; program; form letter.
- Women, 1941 (Box 62, Folder 12)
  Form letters from IWO, National Director of Women's Work, re pending legislation.
- Women's Department, National, 1942 (Box 62, Folder 13)
  6 page "Mother's Day - 1942 - For Victory"; and 1 page "Proposals on Work of the IWO Women's Clubs".
- Workers Alliance of America, 1938 (Box 62, Folder 14)
  Form letter re conference on unemployment.
- Workmen's Benefit Fund, 1945 (Box 62, Folder 15)
  Minutes of Joint meeting with IWO.
- Young Fraternalists, 1941 (Box 62, Folder 16)
  7 page "Proceedings of the Eastern National Encampment - Young Fraternalists."
- Liquidation - General, 1951-1953 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  Correspondence re Supreme Court ruling listing the IWO as a subversive organization was arbitrary and unconstitutional; 3 page memo from Shipka to Raphael H. Weissman, Esq., re the impact of the injuction upon the overall operations of the IWO; memos re i
- Liquidation - Illinois, 1950-1951 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  Court documents; correspondence with Illinois Department of Insurance requesting list of all lodges in the state.
- Liquidation - Illinois, 1950-1953 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  Court documents and routine correspondence.
- Liquidation - New York State, 1951-1953 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  Includes releases, form letter, 4 page release "War with Russia Given as Grounds for Liquidation of Fraternal Order" by Elmer Bendiner; letters to Alfred Bohlinger, Superintendent of Insurance, in reply to his letter which was sent to all locals - IWO rep
- Liquidation - New York State, 1951-1953 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  Correspondence; form letters to lodges re steps in fight for life of the Order; fact sheet and questions re Albany hearing; 3 page "Statement to the Members of the New York State Senate and Assembly by a Delegation of the IWO Policyholders Protective Comm
- Liquidation - New York State, 1952-1953 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  Releases; 57 page "Analysis of Haley Report - for Purposes of Cross Examination."
- Liquidation - New York State, 1950-1953 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  Correspondence re request for approval of purchase of building for IWO home office use and routine re hearings, membership, requests for information; broadsides; IWO News Bulletin, 2 issues,(April 1951 and May 1951); 3 page list of signers of petition Req
- Liquidation - New York State - Court Documents, 1950 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  Includes petitions, order to show cause, briefs.
- Liquidation - New York State - Court Documents, 1950 (Box 62, Folder 17)
- Liquidation - New York State - Court Documents, 1950 (Box 63, Folder 1)
- Liquidation - New York State - Court Documents, 1950-1953 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  Briefs, opinions, reports.
- Liquidation - New York State - Court Documents, 1950-1953 (Box 24, Folder 2)
- Liquidation - New York State - Court Documents, 1950-1953 (Box 24, Folder 3)
- Liquidation - New York State - Court Documents, 1950-1953 (Box 24, Folder 4)
- Liquidation - New York State - Court Documents, 1950-1953 (Box 24, Folder 5)
- Liquidation - New York State - Court Documents, 1950-1953 (Box 24, Folder 6)
- Liquidation - New York State - Court Documents, 1950-1953 (Box 24, Folder 7)
- Liquidation - New York State - Court Documents, 1950-1953 (Box 24, Folder 8)
- Liquidation - New York State - Court Documents, 1950-1953 (Box 24, Folder 9)
- Liquidation - New York State - Court Documents, 1950-1953 (Box 24, Folder 10)
- Liquidation - New York State - Court Documents, 1950-1953 (Box 24, Folder 11)
- Liquidation - New York State - Court Documents, 1950-1953 (Box 24, Folder 12)
- Liquidation - New York State - Court Documents, 1950-1953 (Box 24.1, Folder 1)
- Liquidation - New York State - Court Documents, 1950-1953 (Box 24.1, Folder 2)
- Liquidation - New York State - Court Documents, 1950-1953 (Box 24.1, Folder 3)
- Liquidation - New York State - Court Documents, 1950-1953 (Box 24.1, Folder 4)
- Liquidation - New York State - Court Documents, 1950-1953 (Box 24.1, Folder 5)
- Liquidation - New York State - Court Documents, 1950-1953 (Box 24.1, Folder 6)
- Liquidation - New York State - Court Documents, 1950-1953 (Box 24.1, Folder 7)
- Liquidation - New York State - Court Documents, 1950-1953 (Box 24.1, Folder 8)
- Liquidation - New York State - Court Documents, 1950-1953 (Box 24.1, Folder 9)
- Liquidation - New York State - Court Documents, 1950-1953 (Box 24.1, Folder 10)
- Liquidation - New York State - Court Documents, 1950-1953 (Box 24.1, Folder 11)
- Liquidation - New York State - Court Documents, 1950-1953 (Box 24.1, Folder 12)
- Liquidation - New York State - Court Documents, 1950-1953 (Box 24.1, Folder 13)
- Liquidation - New York State - Court Documents, 1950-1953 (Box 24.1, Folder 14)
- Liquidation - New York State - Court Documents, 1950-1953 (Box 24.1, Folder 15)
- Liquidation - New York State - Court Documents, 1950-1953 (Box 24.1, Folder 16)
- Liquidation - American-Russian Fraternal Society. (Box 25, Folder 1)
- Liquidation - Carpatho-Russian Society. (Box 25, Folder 2)
- Liquidation - Croatian Society. (Box 25, Folder 3)
- Liquidation - Douglass-Lincoln Fraternal Society. (Box 25, Folder 4)
- Liquidation - Garibaldi Society. (Box 25, Folder 5)
- Liquidation - IWO Files from Sam Milgrom. (Box 25, Folder 6)
- Liquidation - IWO Translation of Loose Matters on Top of Files. (Box 25, Folder 7)
- Liquidation - JPFO Cabinet D-8. (Box 25, Folder 8)
- Liquidation - JPFO Cabinet D-9. (Box 25, Folder 9)
- Liquidation - JPFO Translations, etc. - Cabinet D-10. (Box 25, Folder 10)
- Liquidation - JPFO Cabinet G-22. (Box 25, Folder 11)
- Liquidation - Jewish Young Fraternalists Cabinet D-36. (Box 26, Folder 1)
- Liquidation - Albert E. Kahn Files, Cabinet D-207. (Box 26, Folder 2)
- Liquidation - Polish. (Box 26, Folder 3)
- Liquidation - Serbian American Federation. (Box 26, Folder 4)
- Liquidation - Slovak Workers Society. (Box 26, Folder 5)
- Liquidation - "Spanish Original Copy." (Box 26, Folder 6)
- Liquidation - Ukrainian-American Fraternal Union Cabinet D-66 and D-67 (Box 26, Folder 7)
- Liquidation - Ukrainian-American Fraternal UnionCabinet D-66 and D-67 (Box 26, Folder 8)
- Liquidation - "Cabinet D-50 - IWO." (Box 26, Folder 9)
- Liquidation - Miscellaneous Material Transferred from Empty Cabinets - General Lodges. (Box 26, Folder 10)
- Liquidation - Miscellaneous, 1949-1956 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  3 page manuscript to "General Council" re special meeting called because of the "Fraternal Report" issued by the New York Insurance Department; IWO property, Arrow Farms, Inc., legal correspondence; handwritten notes re textbook Workers School - We Learn
- Liquidation - Miscellaneous, 1951-1953 (Box 63, Folder 1)
  Letters of support and miscellaneous. (Mostly Yiddish.)
- Liquidation - Miscellaneous, 1950-1956 (Box 63, Folder 2)
  Yiddish and English support letters, clippings, financial data and miscellaneous.
- Liquidation - Mail Received by Insurance Department, 1953-1956 (Box 63, Folder 3)
  Correspondence re loans to Camp Lakeland and Camp Kinderland; legal notices; insurance claims; real estate; release sent to all lodges by New York State Insurance Department re liquidating and miscellaneous notes.
- 2 page "Declaration of Principles Adopted by the JPFO of the IWO, Inc." (Box 27, Folder 1)
- Constitution and By-laws, 7 pages (Box 27, Folder 1a)
- Minutes, National Executive Committee, 1930-1949 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  Early minutes (1930-31) discuss funeral fund, establishment of a National Cemetery Fund, land purchase for cemetery (non-sectarian); 1939 - discusses budget proposals; 1945 - re 15th Anniversary of the Order, membership drive, the Order in Canada, JPFO of
- Minutes, National Executive Committee, 1930-1949 (Box 27, Folder 3)
- Resident Board - Minutes, 1940-1947 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  1940 - movement for social security, replacement of editor of Fraternal Outlook "who can better fill the present need of the magazine"; 1941 - membership campaign, Dies attack, the war effort; 1946 - report on Peace Conference in Washington, reports on me
- Resident Board Minutes, 1948-1953 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  1948 - National Leadership Training School, old age home, membership campaign, cultural work, report of the schools, crisis in Palestine; 1949 - report on Pavis Peace Congress, Centenary of Emma Lazarus, old age home, membership drive; 1950 - 20th Anniversary
- Reports to National Board by General Secretary R. Saltzman, 1946-1948 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  1946 - Hitlerism, Jewish Labor Committee, contribution of JPFO relief effort, unity movement, political elections building of the order; 1947 - 1946 elections and the Jewish people, aftermaths of the war, American-Jewish Conference and the Jewish Congress
- Reports to National Board, 1935-1948 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  In Yiddish.
- Reports to National Board, 1935-1948 (Box 27, Folder 8)
- Reports to National Board, 1935-1948 (Box 63, Folder 4)
- 4th Convention, 1938 (Box 27.1, Folder 1)
  Includes report of Yiddish Section (in Yiddish).
- 5th and 6th Conventions, 1940-1944 (Box 27.1, Folder 2)
  Includes reports and speeches in Yiddish with the exception of "Committee on English-Speaking Work Report" by George Starr (1944), p. 81-94, discusses Jewish contributions to America, Jewish culture, growth of lodges, schools, youth movement, need for Jewish
- Report of Pre-Convention Problems, 1947 (Box 27.1, Folder 4)
  In Yiddish - pre-presidential election of 1948.
- 7th Convention - Minutes, 1947 (Box 27.1, Folder 5)
  Held at Camp Kinderland, 48 pages, includes reports from secretaries of lodges and chairmen of various committees, and resolutions.
- 7th Convention - Minutes, 1947 (Box 27.1, Folder 6)
  In Yiddish. Held at Camp Kinderland, 48 pages, includes reports from secretaries of lodges and chairmen of various committees, and resolutions.
- 7th Convention - Reports and Speeches, 1947 (Box 27.1, Folder 7)
  Includes corrected drafts of reports and speeches, R. Saltzman report to the 7th Convention, "Looking to the Future," 31 pages.
- 7th Convention - Speech, 1947 (Box 27.1, Folder 8)
  Order Convention by P. Novick in Yiddish.
- 7th Convention - Miscellaneous, 1947 (Box 63, Folder 5)
  Includes "Plan for English-Speaking Lodges", "Pre-Convention Discussion Outline", and miscellaneous.
- Report of R. Salzman on Plenary Session - 20th Anniversary of IWO in Yiddish., 1949 (Box 63, Folder 6)
- 8th Convention, 1951 (Box 63, Folder 7)
  Includes 3 page "Call to the Convention" in both English and Yiddish, forms for delegates, and form letter.
- Emma Lazarus Division - Action Letter, 1946-1947 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  Newsletter published by Emma Lazarus Division, Women's Organization of the JPFO.
- Emma Lazarus Division - Correspondence - General, 1945-1948 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  Includes statement of Division re FEPC, outline for discussion of International Women's Day, and routine correspondence.
- Emma Lazarus Division - Membership Drives, 1946-1947 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  Form letters re membership drives.
- Emma Lazarus Division - Minutes, 1946-1947 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  Includes minutes for June 9, 1946 and August 21, 1947
- Emma Lazarus Division - Miscellaneous, 1946-1949 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  Includes bulletin, newsletter, form letters, leaflets, release.
- Cultural Conference Committee, 1948-1949 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  Includes financial statements, programs, clipping, 8 page "Main Address to Cultural Conference - Answer to a People Calling" by Morris Schappes.
- Jewish Community Council of Detroit, 1945 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  Correspondence re JPFO contributing to Civic Defense Fund Drive - requests that none of the funds be given to the Jewish Labor Committee which is a "destructive force within Jewish life."
- Los Angeles Jewish City Committee, 1950 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  Includes 5 page "Bulletin of the City Committee of the JPFO, Los Angeles, California, February 1950."
- New York Jewish City Committee, 1940-1946 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  Includes correspondence (mostly Yiddish), program, announcements, form letters.
- Committees - Minutes, Miscellaneous, 1946-1953 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  Includes August 1947 minutes of the 2nd meeting of the National Youth Committee of the JPFO; Committee on English-Speaking Work, February 1946; City Legislative Action Committee of the City Youth Executive, May 1946; Joint Distributive Committee, release,
- Kahn, Albert E. - President, 1946-1948 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  Correspondence re situation in Poland; Jews in Palestine; form letters; memo, "Statement on Second Session of World Jewish Congress, 1948, to Executive Committee Members."
- Pevzner, Sam - National Activities Director and Editor of the Jewish Fraternalists, 1946-1948 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  Letter to Pevzner from Peter Seeger, National Director, People's Songs, Inc. requesting his presence at their first National Convention; form letters re various activities; and routine.
- Rymer, E. N. - National Director Youth and Veterans Activities, 1946-1950 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  Correspondence form letters re meetings, conferences, membership and routine.
- Saltzman, Rubin - General Secretary, 1938-1941 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  Routine correspondence, letter from M. H. McIntyre, Secretary to the President of U.S., thanking Saltzman for patriotic support, 11/11/41
- Saltzman, Rubin - General Secretary, 1942-1943 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  Includes 4 page letter from Saltzman to Meyer M. Weisgal re asking for re-consideration of the IWO's application for membership on the Executive Committee of the American Jewish Assembly and letter from Russian Ambassador, letter to Governor Dewey re impr
- Saltzman, Rubin, 1944 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  2 page "Nora Van Leewen Zhitlowsky, (A Short Biographical Sketch)"; correspondence and form letters re July 4th celebration; correspondence with Nora Zhitlowsky re her lectures in various cities, letter from War Department re segregation of races.
- Saltzman, Rubin, 1945 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  Correspondence re financial contribution to the American Jewish Conference, Hadassah, Jewish Council for War Relief and routine.
- Saltzman, Rubin, 1946 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  Correspondence re new IWO organizations in Fresno, California and Tucson, Arizona, setting up Jewish Orphans home in Poland, correspondence re a monument to Sholem Aleichem and routine.
- Saltzman, Rubin, 1946 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  Correspondence with Nora Zhitlowsky re routine and other routine correspondence.
- Saltzman, Rubin - Tour, 1946 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  Mostly re arrangements for tours.
- Saltzman, Rubin, 1946-1947 (Box 29, Folder 11)
  In Yiddish. Correspondence re the Children's relief and Rehabilitation Homes in Belgium and France and the events in Warsaw, and routine.
- Saltzman, Rubin, 1947 (Box 29, Folder 12)
  Letter from Joseph Brainin, 3/26/47 to Saltzmann re whether the JPFO should include an effective department to counteract anti- Semitism in the U.S.; 5/15/47 letter from Brainin suggesting "the Committee of Writer to tender a dinner in honor of Gromyko"; 4
- Saltzman, Rubin, 1948-1949 (Box 29, Folder 13)